Is it possible to be too clever?
有没有可能太聪明了呢？
Could it be that a big brain is actually a dangerous asset?
会不会是说拥有一个发达的大脑实际上是一种危险的资产呢？
Whilst the brainy human species goes from strength to strength, a study suggests that having an abundance of grey matter directly increases the risk of extinction in our mammal cousins.
虽然聪明的人类物种正日益强大，但一项研究表明，拥有大量的灰质会直接增加我们的近亲哺乳动物面临灭绝的风险。
Biologist Manuela Gonzalez-Suarez, from the University of Reading, says that big brains come with a clear downside.
雷丁大学的生物学家曼努埃拉·冈萨雷斯-苏亚雷斯表示，大脑发达具备明显的弊端。
"The cost is too high," she told BBC Future.
“代价太大了，”她告诉《BBC未来》栏目。
They require a lot of energy to grow and maintain.
大脑的生长和维持需要消耗大量的能量。
Large-brained animals also have longer gestational periods, meaning they produce fewer offspring.
大脑发达的动物也有更长的妊娠期，这意味着它们生育的后代较少。
And their young need greater parental attention until they become independent.
而且它们的幼崽在独立之前需要父母更多的照料。
These traits mean "populations cannot grow fast, or quickly compensate for additional mortality," she says.
她表示，这些特征意味着“种群数量无法快速增长，或者无法迅速弥补额外的死亡数量。”
In short, big brains are an investment not all animals can afford.
简而言之，大脑发达是一项并非所有动物都能承受的投资。
And this precarious situation is made worse by the fact that many large mammals are themselves the target of poaching or live in threatened habitats.
而且，许多大型哺乳动物本身就是偷猎的目标，或者生活在受到威胁的栖息地中，这使得这种不稳定的情况变得更糟。
Some animals have long since decided that brains weren't necessary.
有些动物很久以前就认定大脑并非必要。
BBC Future suggests that sponges evolved to lose their brains over time, as they offered no tangible benefits.
《BBC未来》栏目指出，海绵动物随着时间的推移逐渐进化，失去了它们的大脑，因为大脑并没有给它们带来任何切实的好处。
But what about humans?
但是人类呢？
We are the most intelligent species on Earth.
我们是地球上最聪明的物种。
We have tamed the natural environment, developed incredible technologies, and settled across almost every corner of the planet.
我们已经征服了自然环境，开发出了令人惊叹的技术，并且几乎在地球的每个角落都有了定居点。
But all this may be exacerbating the problem for other species.
但所有这些可能正在加剧其他物种所面临的问题。
Gonzalez-Suarez says: "It is our collective responsibility as scientists who study megafauna to act to prevent their decline."
冈萨雷斯-苏亚雷斯说：“作为研究大型动物的科学家，我们有共同的责任采取行动防止它们的数量减少。”
Time to put our big brains to good use.
是时候好好利用我们发达的大脑了。